The Duggan Family Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Duggan Family Papers
1908 - 2009
1962 - 1980
NPKMC-222-107
7.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Stephen Pierce Duggan, Jr.; Beatrice Abbott "Smokey" Duggan; Mary Vance Duggan; Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC)
Stephen Duggan was a born in White Plains, NY. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy, Harvard University and Columbia University. At Columbia he met Beatrice Abbott, whom he married in 1936 and had four children with. Stephen graduated from Columbia Law School and began working at the Wall Street firm of Simpson, Thatcher and Bartlett where he became partner. In 1963-64 both Stephen and Smokey Duggan helped found the Scenic Hudson Preservations Conference – an organization whose mission was the prevention of Consolidated Edison’s plan for a pumped-storage power plant at Storm King Mountain. The case was an important founding moment in the development of environmental law and Stephen Duggan himself is often credited as a pioneer of the concept of environmental interest law. In 1970 Stephen and Smokey Duggan founded the Natural Resources Defense Council, a public interest law firm dedicated to the protection of natural resources. Smokey Duggan was appointed as the NRDC’s representative to the nongovernmental organization of the United Nations. The Duggan Family Papers is a collection of letters, legal documents, financial records, administrative correspondence, published information, newspaper clippings and photographs relating to the lives of Stephen and Smokey Duggan and their involvement in the Storm King Case and the Natural Resources Defense Council. Also included is the collected research and notes of Mary Vance Duggan resulting from her screenplay on the Duggans and the campaign against the Con-Ed plan for Storm King Mountain.
Collection Overview
The Duggan Family Papers is a collection of letters, legal documents, financial records, administrative correspondence, published information, newspaper clippings and photographs relating to the lives of Stephen and Smokey Duggan and their involvement in the Storm King Case and the Natural Resources Defense Council. Also included is the collected research and notes of Mary Vance Duggan resulting from her screenplay on the Duggans and the campaign against the Con-Ed plan for Storm King Mountain.
Acquisitions Information
The Duggan Family Papers were donated to Marist College by the Duggan family in 2011.
Historical Note
Stephen Duggan was born in White Plains, New York in 1909 and spent most of his childhood in Greenwich, Connecticut where he enjoyed sailing on the Long Island Sound with his older brother Laurence. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy, Harvard University and Columbia University where his father, Stephen Duggan, Sr., was dean of the Political Science Department and a director of the Council on Foreign Relations. At Columbia he met Beatrice Abbott, the granddaughter of Congregationalist theologian Lyman Abbott. Beatrice had attended Vassar College where she was given the nickname “Smokey.” They married in 1936 and had four children. Stephen graduated from Columbia Law School and began working at the Wall Street firm of Simpson, Thatcher and Bartlett where he became partner. His older brother Laurence Duggan worked for the State Department where he helped develop Franklin D. Roosevelt’s “Good Neighbor Policy” toward Latin America. Smokey Duggan dedicated herself to non-profit organizations. Throughout the 1940s and 1950s she worked with the League of Composers, the Storm King School and the Public Education Association and in 1955 she was appointed as a New York Delegate to the White House Conference on Education. In 1958 she co-founded and became the director of National Young Audiences and during the early 1960s she was involved in the early preparations for the fight against the Con-Ed plant at Storm King.
In 1963-64 both Stephen and Smokey Duggan helped found the Scenic Hudson Preservations Conference – an organization whose mission was the prevention of Consolidated Edison’s plan for a pumped-storage power plant at Storm King Mountain. The 1965 Supreme Court Case established the precedent that individuals could sue on behalf of public interest for the preservation and beatification of the natural environment. The case was an important founding moment in the development of environmental law and Stephen Duggan himself is often credited as a pioneer of the concept of environmental interest law. The collection contains correspondence concerning Storm King with many influential figures including: Congressman Robert J. Barry, Senator Clifford P. Case, the Federal Power Commission, Senator Jacob J. Javits, the Lyndon Johnson administration, Senator Kenneth B. Keating, Senator Robert Kennedy, Thomas Lamont, Congressman Richard L. Ottinger, Dr. Nathan M. Pusey, Laurence S. Rockefeller, Alexander Saunders, Secretary of the Interior Stuart L. Udall as well as various Consolidated Edison officials. In 1970 Stephen and Smokey Duggan founded the Natural Resources Defense Council, a public interest law firm dedicated to the protection of natural resources. The organization would offer the professional help of scientists and lawyers to a number of disjointed and fledgling environmental campaigns. Stephen served as Chairman of the Board of Trustees from 1970 until 1980 where he directed the early development of the organization. Smokey Duggan was appointed as the NRDC’s representative to the nongovernmental organization of the United Nations. After the death of Smokey in 1996 and Stephen in 1998 their daughter-in-law Mary Vance Duggan began researching the history of their lives and involvement in the Storm King Case. Parts of this collection were the result of this inquiry. Around 2005 she completed a screenplay based Stephen and Smokey Duggan’s participation in the campaign against Consolidated Edison over Storm King Mountain.
There are no restrictions on this collection
The collection is arranged into secen series: 1. Documents pertaining to the Storm King Case, seperated into six subseries, 2. Documents pertaining to the National Resources Defense Council (NRDC), seperated into four subseries, with subseries 2.2 having a subseries and subseries 2.3 having three subseries, and subseries 2.3.3 having two subseries, 3. Duggan Family Person Papers, seperated into five subersies, 4. Clippings, seperated into 6 subseries, 5. Books and Pamphlets, 6. Graphic Materials, seperated into four subseries, and 7. Documents concerning the screenplay written by Mary Vance Duggan, seperated into five subseries.
Series and subseries are arranged by subject or chronologically
- 1. Documents pertaining to the Storm King Case, 1908 - 1992; 1; Boxes: 1 - 4 Folders: 1 - 45, 1 - 45, 1 - 45, 1 - 9
  Series contains correspondence, fundraising and finances documents, legal documents, Scenic Hudson information packets, articles and clippings, and a topical file
  Suberies are seperated by subject, most subseries arranged chronologically
  - Subseries 1.1: Storm King Correspondence, 1962 - 1970; 1.1; Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 11
    Chronological
    - Draft of letter to Mrs. John F. Kennedy, Georgetown, Maryland, undated (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1962 October (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1962 November (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1962 December (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963 January (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963 February (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 March (Folder 7, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 April (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 May (Folder 9, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 June (Folder 10, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 July (Folder 11, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 August (Folder 12, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 September (Folder 13, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 October (Folder 14, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 November (Folder 15, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1964 December (Folder 16, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 January (Folder 17, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 February (Folder 18, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 March (Folder 19, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 December (Folder 20, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 February (Folder 21, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 February - March (Folder 22, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 March (Folder 23, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 April (Folder 24, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 May (Folder 25, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 June (Folder 26, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 August (Folder 27, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 September (Folder 28, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 November (Folder 29, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 December (Folder 30, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 31, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Folder 32, Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1971 September (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2: Fundraising and Finances, 1964 - 1970; 1.2; Boxes: 1 - 2 Folders: 12 - 45, 1 - 36
    - Financial documents, 1964 January (Folder 34, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 June (Folder 35, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 July (Folder 36, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 August (Folder 37, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 September (Folder 38, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 October (Folder 39, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 November (Folder 40, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1964 December (Folder 41, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1965 January (Folder 42, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1965 February (Folder 43, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1965 March (Folder 44, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1965 April (Folder 45, Box 1)
    - Financial documents, 1965 May (Folder 1, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 June (Folder 2, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 July (Folder 3, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 August (Folder 4, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 September (Folder 5, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 October (Folder 6, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1965 November (Folder 7, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 January (Folder 8, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 February (Folder 9, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 March (Folder 10, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 April (Folder 11, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 May (Folder 12, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 June (Folder 13, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 July (Folder 14, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 August (Folder 15, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 September (Folder 16, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 October (Folder 17, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 November (Folder 18, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1966 December (Folder 19, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 January (Folder 20, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 March (Folder 21, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 April (Folder 22, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 June (Folder 23, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 September (Folder 24, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 October (Folder 25, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 November (Folder 26, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1967 December (Folder 27, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1968 January (Folder 28, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1968 May (Folder 29, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1968 June (Folder 30, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1968 August (Folder 31, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1968 September (Folder 32, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1969 June (Folder 33, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1969 October (Folder 34, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, 1970 January (Folder 35, Box 2)
    - Financial documents, undated (Folder 36, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.3: Legal Documents, 1965 - 1971; 1.3; Box: 2 Folders: 37 - 45
    - Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1965: Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., v. Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference (Folder 37, Box 2)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit: Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, v. Federal Power Commission and Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., 1965 (Folder 38, Box 2)
    - United States of America Federal power Commission Order Permitting Intervention, Consolidated Edison Company of New York - Project no. 2338, 1966 March 17 (Folder 39, Box 2)
    - State of New York: In Senate, Act creating the Hudson River Valley Commission, 1966 March 24 (Folder 40, Box 2)
    - United States of America before the Federal Power Commission: Petition of the Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference for Permission to Intervene [2 copies], circa 1966 (Folder 41, Box 2)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit: Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference v. Federal Power Commission and Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., 1970 - 1971 (Folder 42, Box 2)
    - Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1971: Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference v. Federal Power Commission (Folder 43, Box 2)
    - Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1971: Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference v. Federal Power Commission (Folder 44, Box 2)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the First Circuit: Commerce Oil Refining Corp., v. William W. Miner et al., undated (Folder 45, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.4: Scenic Hudson Information Packets, 1966 - 1969; 1.4; Box: 3 Folders: 1 - 8
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference: Position Report, 1966 March (Folder 1, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference: Important new developments in the fight to save Storm King, 1966 March 31 (Folder 2, Box 3)
    - Cornwall and the Con Edison Project - Draft - [3 copies], circa 1966 (Folder 3, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, circa 1966 (Folder 4, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference: Con Ed should NOT build at Storm King, here is why, circa 1966 (Folder 5, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, Information Kit: The Preservation of Storm King Mountain, circa 1966 (Folder 6, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference - Press release concerning sloop Clearwater, circa 1969 (Folder 7, Box 3)
    - Are you a misinformed bird watcher, nature faker, lang grabber, and militant adversary of progress, undated (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.5: Articles and Clippings, 1956 - 1992; 1.5; Box: 3 Folders: 9 - 29
    - American Forests, vol. 71, no. 4, April 1965; featuring article titled, The Battle of the Hudson, by Turner Lawrence, (p. 12-15) (Folder 9, Box 3)
    - Editorial: The Storm King Opinion - A Stunning Conservation Victory,in American Forests, March 1966 [2 copies] (Folder 10, Box 3)
    - The Hudson: Summary Report of the Hudson River Valley Commission, 1966 (Folder 11, Box 3)
    - Precedent on the Hudson, by Maxwell C. Wheat, Jr., in the Sierra Club Bulletin, March 1966 (Folder 12, Box 3)
    - Audubon, vol. 70, no. 4, July/August 1968; featuring article titled, Storm over Storm King,by Laurence Pringle, (p. 60-73) (Folder 13, Box 3)
    - Environmentalism and the Leisure Class: Protecting birds, fishes, and above all, social privilege, by William Tucker, in Harper's Magazine, 1977 (Folder 14, Box 3)
    - The Cornwall Hydroelectric Project, reprinted articles from the Cornwall Local, 1992 (Folder 15, Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1956 (Folder 16, Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1964 (Folder 17, Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1965 (Folder 18, Box 3)
    - Clippings, undated (Folder 19, Box 3)
    - Clippings - original, 1964 (Folder 20, Box 3)
    - Clippings - preserved, 1964 (Folder 21, Box 3)
    - Clippings - original, 1965 (Folder 22, Box 3)
    - Clippings - preserved, 1965 (Folder 23, Box 3)
    - Clippings - original, 1966 (Folder 24, Box 3)
    - Clippings - preserved, 1966 (Folder 25, Box 3)
    - Clippings - original, 1971 (Folder 26, Box 3)
    - Clippings - preserved, 1971 (Folder 27, Box 3)
    - Clippings - original, undated (Folder 28, Box 3)
    - Clippings - preserved, undated (Folder 29, Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.6: Topical File, 1908 - 1985; 1.6; Boxes: 4 Folders: 30 - 45, 1 - 9
    - Black Rock Forest, 1980 (Folder 30, Box 3)
    - Black Rock Forest, 1987 - 1989 (Folder 31, Box 3)
    - Details of campaign against Con Edison plan, undated (Folder 32, Box 3)
    - Federal Power Commission Proceedings Concerning the Storm King Plant [timeline], circa 1981 (Folder 33, Box 3)
    - Hostile description of Con Edison's plan for Black Rock Forest, undated (Folder 34, Box 3)
    - International Conference on Pumped Storage Development and Its Environmental Effects, 1971 (Folder 35, Box 3)
    - Legal research on Public Right of Passage, circa 1966 (Folder 36, Box 3)
    - Local Area History, undated (Folder 37, Box 3)
    - Local Area History: Black Rock Reservoir, 1908 November 5 (Folder 38, Box 3)
    - Local Area History: Black Rock Reservoir, 1908 November 6 (Folder 39, Box 3)
    - Local Area History: Consolidation of Cornwall Village, 1922 March 17 (Folder 40, Box 3)
    - Notes from Meeting of April 6th, 1966, 1966 April 6 (Folder 41, Box 3)
    - Resolution memorializing Congress to establish the Hudson Highlands National Park, undated (Folder 42, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson, 1966 April 15 (Folder 43, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Foundation, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation, 1966 (Folder 44, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference - Memorandum re Decisions at Century Club Meeting, 1968 June 13 (Folder 45, Box 3)
    - Scenic Hudson [items found in folder], 1985 (Folder 1, Box 4)
    - Scenic Hudson [items found in folder], 1985 (Folder 2, Box 4)
    - Scenic Hudson, undated (Folder 3, Box 4)
    - Special Pertinent State Laws - F.P.C. Docket no., Exhibit C, undated (Folder 4, Box 4)
    - Statement of Rod Vandivert, Executive Director, Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, at air pollution hearings, held by Joint Legislative Committee on Natural Resources and Natural Beauty, 270 Broadway, New York, N.Y., 1965 December 14 (Folder 5, Box 4)
    - Typed notes, likely meeting notes, undated (Folder 6, Box 4)
    - Types notes regarding the gift of the Stillmans to the Palisades Interstate Park and questioning the legality of the gift to Con Edison, undated (Folder 7, Box 4)
    - Woods Hole Meeting - Attendance and handwritten notes, 1976 September 26 - October 1 (Folder 8, Box 4)
    - Miscellany, undated (Folder 9, Box 4)
- 2. Documents Pertaining to the National Resources Defense Council (NRDC), 2; linear feet Boxes: 4 - 9 Folders: 10 - 51, 1 - 53, 1 - 46, 1 - 42, 1 - 35, 1 - 21
  Series contains General NRDC documents, NRDC international programss documents, documents from the United Nations, and a NRDC topical file
  Subseries are seperated by subject, some are arranged chronologically
  - Subseries 2.1: General NRDC Documents, 1978 - 2002; 2.1; Box: 4 Folders: 10 - 32
    - NRDC Five-Year Report, 1970-1975 [pamphlet] (Folder 10, Box 4)
    - Letter to Dr. Thomas J. Connolly regarding his criticism of the NRDC, 1976 February 19 (Folder 11, Box 4)
    - NRDC World Environmental Alert, vol. 1, no. 1 [newsletter], 1976 March 1 (Folder 12, Box 4)
    - Letter to Howard R. Dressner of the Ford Foundation to Steven Duggan concerning excerpt from the Senate Judiciary Committee Hearings, 1976 September 28 (Folder 13, Box 4)
    - NRDC Board of Trustees, 1977 (Folder 14, Box 4)
    - Memo: Environmental Group Awarded Largest Grant in Public Interest Law History, 1978 October 23 (Folder 15, Box 4)
    - Attorney General's Award for Public Service presented to Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc. by James W. Moorman, Assistant Attorney General, 1979 November 2 (Folder 16, Box 4)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc. - Docket -, 1975 January (Folder 17, Box 4)
    - Review Outlook: Public Interest Law in The Wall Street Journal, 1979 December 17 (Folder 18, Box 4)
    - Statement of Roque Sevilla, Fundacion Natura Quito, Ecuador before the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research and Foreign Agriculture, Committee on Agriculture - United States House of Representatives, Washington, D.C. - concerning pesticide exports, 1983 October 6 (Folder 19, Box 4)
    - Washington's Lobbying Groups - How They Rate, reprint of the article that ranked NRDC #1 in The Environmental Forum, vol.3, no. 12, 1985 April (Folder 20, Box 4)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council Fifteen-Year Report, 1970-1985 (Folder 21, Box 4)
    - Obituary for Harold L. Oram, NRDC fundraiser, 1990 August 23 (Folder 22, Box 4)
    - Clipping with photo on DRDC headquarters dedication, 1991 December 11 (Folder 23, Box 4)
    - A Force of Nature: NRDC - 25 Years on Earth [pamphlet], 1996 (Folder 24, Box 4)
    - Environmental Law: What Started It All? [from the NRDC website], circa 2002 (Folder 25, Box 4)
    - Excerpt from The New Yorker article featuring the NRDC, undated (Folder 26, Box 4)
    - Letter from Joan V [McCall] to Smokey [Duggan] regarding grants on the General Services Foundation, undated (Folder 27, Box 4)
    - Responsible Militancy - The Anatomy of a Public Interest Law Firm, by John H. Adams, undated (Folder 28, Box 4)
    - The Role of the Public Interest Law Firm in Environmental Protection, undated (Folder 29, Box 4)
    - Wall Street Journal article: Group's Influence on U.S. Environmental Laws, Policies Earns it a Reputation as a Shadow EPA, undated (Folder 30, Box 4)
    - Your Dollars and Environments Sense, Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc. [pamphlet], undated (Folder 31, Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, undated (Folder 32, Box 4)
  - Subseries 2.2: NRDC International Program, 1975 - 1980; 2.2; Box: 4 - 5 Folders: 33 - 51, 1 - 19
    Series contains programs and RBF questionaire materials
    By Subject
    - RBF Questionnaire, 2.2.1; Boxes: 5 - 6 Folders: 20 - 53, 1 - 19
      - Domestic list of organizations, undated (Folder 19, Box 5)
      - Foreign list of organizations, undated (Folder 20, Box 5)
      - Domestic questionnaire draft, undated (Folder 21, Box 5)
      - Foreign questionnaire draft, undated (Folder 22, Box 5)
      - Five blank questionnaire, undated (Folder 23, Box 5)
      - African Wildlife Leadership Foundation, 1975 (Folder 24, Box 5)
      - Alberta Wilderness Association, undated (Folder 25, Box 5)
      - American Rivers Conservation Council, undated (Folder 26, Box 5)
      - The Arctic Institute of North America, undated (Folder 27, Box 5)
      - Arkansas Game and Fish Commission, undated (Folder 28, Box 5)
      - The Asia Foundation, 1975 (Folder 29, Box 5)
      - Associazione nazionale italia nostra, undated (Folder 30, Box 5)
      - Australian Conservation Foundation, 1975 (Folder 31, Box 5)
      - Canadian Scientific Pollution and Environmental Control Society, 1975 (Folder 32, Box 5)
      - Canadian Wildlife Federation, 1975 (Folder 33, Box 5)
      - Center for Law and Social Policy, 1975 (Folder 34, Box 5)
      - Civic Trust, 1975 (Folder 35, Box 5)
      - The Conservation Society, 1975 (Folder 36, Box 5)
      - Council for the Protection of Rural England, 1975 (Folder 37, Box 5)
      - Energy Probe, University of Toronto, undated (Folder 38, Box 5)
      - Environmental Action Foundation, 1975 (Folder 39, Box 5)
      - European Economic Bureau, 1975 (Folder 40, Box 5)
      - Executive Office of the President, Council on Environmental Quality, 1975 (Folder 41, Box 5)
      - The Federation of Ontario Naturalists, 1975 (Folder 42, Box 5)
      - Fund for Animals, 1975 (Folder 43, Box 5)
      - ICBP [International Centre for Birds of Prey?], undated (Folder 44, Box 5)
      - Inter-environnement [Belgium], 1975 (Folder 45, Box 5)
      - Friends of the Earth [Thailand], 1975 (Folder 46, Box 5)